<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Mitchell Chatterjee</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu3049596157658489136.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration to Agentic LLM Retrieval &amp; Summarization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/rag-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/rag-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At JSI I led the migration from a proprietary orchestration framework to an agentic architecture using Agno and LangChain. The goal was to build a modular, LLM-based retrieval and summarization system integrated with MCP and deployable on-premises across customer sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem&#34;&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing orchestration was monolithic and hard to maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieval quality and latency at scale (billions of multimodal records) were poor for real-time operational use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopted a modular agentic approach using Agno and LangChain for orchestration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built streaming ingestion pipelines to embed audio, text, and images into a vector store (FAISS/HNSW).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented hybrid search (dense + sparse) and chunking strategies to improve recall and relevance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a summarization agent to synthesize results, and an evaluation pipeline (DeepEval + A/B) to measure relevance and latency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;architecture-high-level&#34;&gt;Architecture (high level)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ingest: Kafka-based event ingestion for multimodal records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preprocessing: audio → ASR → text; images → OCR/CLIP embeddings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embeddings: per-modality encoders, unified vector representation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vector Store: FAISS/HNSW with sharding for scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orchestration: Agno &amp;amp; LangChain agents sequence retrieval, grounding, summarization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving: on-prem deployments with GPU acceleration and autoscaling policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Served retrieval &amp;amp; summarization at low-latency for operational workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scaled to billions of records with near real-time updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluated with DeepEval and A/B tests to tune models and rerankers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal architectures and code available upon request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Cardiovascular Arrhythmia Detection - Automated ECG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/automated_ecg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/automated_ecg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the official code repository accompanying the paper titled Toward Robust Automated Cardiovascular Arrhythmia Detection using Self-supervised Learning and 1-Dimensional Vision Transformers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project developed a robust automated cardiovascular arrhythmia detection system using self-supervised pretraining and 1D vision transformer architectures tailored for ECG signals. The system emphasizes reliability under distribution shift and low-labeled-data regimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dataset--artifacts&#34;&gt;Dataset &amp;amp; Artifacts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public datasets: (see repository for dataset details and preprocessing scripts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code: 
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper: Toward Robust Automated Cardiovascular Arrhythmia Detection using Self-supervised Learning and 1-Dimensional Vision Transformers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-supervised pretraining on large unlabeled ECG corpora&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1D Vision Transformer fine-tuning for classification and detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Augmentation strategies, calibration, and uncertainty estimation for safer clinical deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieved state-of-the-art robustness across held-out datasets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrated improved calibration and lower false positive rates in low-label settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;relevance&#34;&gt;Relevance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work underpins my research focus on medical AI and time-series modelling, and complements my engineering work on large-scale retrieval systems by bringing rigorous evaluation and robustness-first design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Leader Election in a Ring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/leader_election/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/leader_election/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is an implementation of the min-max and min-max+ algorithms for distributed leader election in a ring. The example pictured above is flexible, the user can specify any ring size and any number of originators.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
